<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DIS 2019</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on DIS 2019</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ACM Designing Interactive Systems 2019</title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>The ACM conference on Designing Interactive Systems (DIS) is the premier international and interdisciplinary conference encompassing all issues related to the design and deployment of interactive systems where designers, artists, theorists, psychologists, user experience researchers, systems engineers and many more come together to debate and shape the future of interaction systems research, design, and practice.
The theme for ACM DIS2019 is &amp;ldquo;Contesting Borders and Intersections.&amp;rdquo; Both borders and intersections are simultaneously about separation, margins, and friction as well as opportunities, promises, and imaginaries where alternative and diverse modes of engagements can be made possible and unfold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted Workshops</title>
      <link>/accepted-workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/accepted-workshops/</guid>
      <description>Invite-only workshops require an access code provided by the workshop organizers. See each workshop page for details. For workshops with Open Registration, attendees may register without an access code. DIS attendees can apply for C&amp;amp;C workshops.  
Sunday, June 23  C&amp;amp;C Workshops  W1: Distributed Creativity in Play [Open Registration] Andrew M. Webb, Katta Spiel, Zach O. Toups, Bill Hamilton, Nic Lupfer, Ross A. Graeber, Wendy E. Mackay</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Art Exhibition</title>
      <link>/artexhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/artexhibition/</guid>
      <description>ACM Creativity and Cognition 2019 and Designing Interactive Systems 2019.  The art exhibition will present artworks that manifest the conferences’ joint themes of Contesting Borders and Intersections and Transformational Creativity. The C&amp;amp;C website has the identical call for participation.

Important Dates     Action Timeline     Art Exhibition: June 25, 2019   Submission Deadline: February 12th, 2019 11:59 PM (UTC)   Notification: April 26th, 2019    Deadlines are specified as Anywhere on Earth time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Proposals</title>
      <link>/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cfp/</guid>
      <description>Papers  Abstract and Title Submission Due: January 15, 2019 (17:00 PST) Full Submissions due: January 18, 2019 (17:00 PST)  Notifications: March 21, 2019  Camera Ready Deadline: April 17, 2019 
Pictorials  Full Submissions Due: January 18, 2019 (23:59 PST)  Notifications: March 21, 2019  Camera Ready Deadline: April 18, 2019 
Workshops  Proposals Due: January 18, 2019 (23:59 PST)  Notifications: March 8, 2019  Camera Ready Deadline: March 22, 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Registration</title>
      <link>/registration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/registration/</guid>
      <description>Attendees can register for one or the other conference individually, or for a significant discount, attendees can go to both conferences by selecting a joint registration. One-day passes provide another option. Workshop fees are additional to conference registration; Workshop attendees must register for at least one day of the conference.
Register Now  
Full Conference Registration (All fees are in USD)
   &amp;nbsp; Early Bird
(ends May 17) Regular Rate</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIS Keynotes</title>
      <link>/dis_keynotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/dis_keynotes/</guid>
      <description>Lisa Nakamura  Keynote Title: Virtual Reality and the Feeling of Virtue: Women of Color Narrators, Enforced Hospitality, and the Leveraging of Empathy
Abstract: Many researchers and evangelists argue that V.R. is fundamentally more “moving” than other media because of users’ visual immersion in navigable worlds and their empathic identification with another visual perspective. (see Rubin, Bailenson). This essay will analyze women of color’s labor as virtual reality’s documentary subjects whose digital presence and hospitality within war-torn, emiserated, and inhospitable scenes such as a Lebanese refugee camp, a favela, and a cucumber farm enables a fantasy of virtuous empathy on the part of the viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIS Program Overview</title>
      <link>/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/overview/</guid>
      <description>Track 2: Stories and Narratives Wednesday, June 26, 11 AM – 12:30 PM Paper: The Stories People Tell About the Home Through IoT Toolkits Arne Berger (Chemnitz University of Technology), Aloha Ambe (Queensland University of Technology), Alessandro Soro (Queensland University of Technology), Dries De Roeck (Studio Dott.), Margot Brereton (QUT) 
Paper: Turker Tales: Integrating Tangential Play into Crowd Work Anna Kasunic (Carnegie Mellon University), Chun-Wei Chiang (West Virginia University), Geoff Kaufman (Carnegie Mellon University), Saiph Savage (West Virginia University)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIS Steering Committee</title>
      <link>/steering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/steering/</guid>
      <description>Steve Harrison, Virginia Tech (Chair)  Shaowen Bardzell, Indiana University  Jack Carroll, Penn State University  Marcus Foth, Queensland University of Technology Brisbane  Kim Halskov, Aarhus University  Wendy Ju, Cornell Tech  Youn-kyung Lim, Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology  Ron Wakkary, Simon Fraser University  Peter Wright, Newcastle University</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIS and C&amp;C accessibility  FAQ</title>
      <link>/accessibility-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/accessibility-faq/</guid>
      <description>How do I communicate accessibility needs to DIS and C&amp;amp;C organizers? Please identify any accommodations you may need at the time of registration through the registration form under the question “Do you have a disability?” If you have additional needs not specified in your registration, please contact the Accessibility Chairs, Stacy Branham and Foad Hamidi, as soon as possible at accessibilitychair@dis2019.acm.org or accessibilitychair@dis2019.acm.org
 Who do I ask if my question is not answered here?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIS2019 Diversity and Inclusion Statement</title>
      <link>/diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/diversity/</guid>
      <description>The open exchange of ideas and the freedom of thought and expression are central to the aims and goals of the DIS 2019 conference. The DIS community commits to providing a harassment-free, accessible, and pleasant conference experience with equity in rights for all. We want every participant to feel welcome, included, and safe at the conference. Moreover, we will do our best to accommodate specific needs such as accessibility, or dietary requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demos</title>
      <link>/demos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/</guid>
      <description>DIS 2019 invites researchers, prototypes and practitioners to submit their work to the DIS 2019 Demo Track. 
The track invites interface or system demonstrations, novel gadgets, techno-craft, and other interactive experiences that critically or creatively explore the conference themes. These should rethink and challenge the conventional modalities of demonstration, preference will be for demos that involve and activate DIS participants. 

Important Dates     Action Timeline     Demo Deadline: February 8, 2019, (23:59 PST)   Extended Demo Deadline: Wednesday, March 27, 2019 (6 days after paper notifications)   Demo Notifications: Monday, April 8, 2019   Camera Ready Deadline: 21 April 2019   DIS 2019 conference: 24-28 June 2019     Demo submissions should be exploratory, provocative, innovative and ambitious.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctoral Consortium</title>
      <link>/consortium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/consortium/</guid>
      <description>The DIS 2019 Doctoral Consortium provides current doctoral candidates unique opportunities to present their projects to receive feedback from, and engage in exchanges with researchers and peers in design-related fields from around the world, in a stimulating, open, and safe environment.
You must be enrolled in a design-related discipline as a doctoral candidate at the time of submitting your application and at the time of the conference. You will get most value from attending if you are already in possession of a clear direction for your thesis but have not yet finished your research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint DIS and C&amp;C Keynote</title>
      <link>/joint_keynote/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/joint_keynote/</guid>
      <description>Tiffany Shlain and Ken Goldberg Keynote Title: Screen Smashing: Iconoclasty in an Age of Illusionary Intelligence Abstract: &amp;ldquo;Late twentieth-century machines have made thoroughly ambiguous the difference between natural and artificial, mind and body, self-developing and externally designed, and many other distinctions that used to apply to organisms and machines. Our machines are disturbingly lively, and we ourselves are frighteningly inert.&amp;rdquo; - Donna Haraway. Simians, Cyborgs, and Women: The Reinvention of Nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizers</title>
      <link>/organizers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/organizers/</guid>
      <description>Conference Chairs Steve Harrison &amp;amp; Shaowen Bardzell  generalchairs [at] dis2019.acm.org
Associate Chairs Steven Dow &amp;amp; Mary Lou Maher (C&amp;amp;C2019 co-chairs)  chairs2019 [at] cc.acm.org
Technical Program Chairs Carman Neustaedter &amp;amp; Deborah Tatar  technicalchairs [at] dis2019.acm.org
Doctoral Consortium Chairs John Bowers &amp;amp; Wendy Ju  dcchairs [at] dis2019.acm.org
Pictorials Chairs Kristina Anderson &amp;amp; Shad Gross  pictorialchairs [at] dis2019.acm.org
Provocations / WIPS Chairs Lone Koefoed Hansen &amp;amp; Norman Su  provocationschairs [at] dis2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper Associate Chairs (ACs)</title>
      <link>/acs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/acs/</guid>
      <description>José Abdelnour Nocera  Morgan Ames  Swamy Ananthanarayan  Simone Barbosa  Scott Bateman  Eric Baumer  Jordan Beck  Mark Blythe  Stacy Branham  Margot Brereton  Sophia Brueckner  Winslow Burleson  Heloisa Candello  John Carroll  Chia-Fang Chung  James Clawson  Aykut Coşkun  Nick Dalton  Laura Devendorf  Tawanna Dillahunt  Tao Dong  Thomas Dylan  Chris Elsden  Laura Forlano  Sarah Fox  Luciano Gamberini  Patricia Garcia  Colin Gray  Sabrina Hauser  Ilyena Hirskyj-Douglas  Guy Hoffman  Trevor Hogan  Jonathan Hook  Kristina Höök  Lara Houston  Anne Kanstrup Kanstrup  Cindy Hsin-Liu Kao  Reuben Kirkham  Neha Kumar  Edward Lank  Amanda Lazar  Christopher Le Dantec  Anamary Leal  Joon Suk Lee  Joonhwan Lee  Silvia Lindtner  Daria Loi  Lindsay MacDonald Vermeulen  Arthi Manohar  Mauro Martino  Michael Muller  Suranga Nanayakkara  Lisa Nathan  Valentina Nisi  William Odom  Hyunjoo Oh  Carolyn Pang  Nadia Pantidi  Claudio Pinhanez  Larissa Pschetz  Daniela Rosner  Kimiko Ryokai  Selma Sabanovic  Daisuke Sakamoto  Corina Sas  Raja Schaar  Thecla Schiphorst  Patrick Shih  Michael Smyth  Marie Louise Søndergaard  Omar Sosa-Tzec  Chris Speed  Katarzyna Stawarz  Dag Svanes  Anthony Tang  Alex Taylor  Martin Tomitsch  Austin Toombs  Cesar Torres  John Vines  Mikael Wiberg  Robert Xiao  Qian Yang  Jude Yew  Daisy Yoo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Papers</title>
      <link>/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/papers/</guid>
      <description>Full papers published at DIS2019 are ACM archival publications and will be made available through the ACM in the Digital Library. DIS 2019 will be held jointly with the Creativity and Cognition (C&amp;amp;C) 2019 conference. There will be some overlapping programs to strengthen the dialogues between these two related communities, however, authors must choose which conference to submit to — submissions will not be shared or moved between C&amp;amp;C and DIS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pictorials</title>
      <link>/pictorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pictorials/</guid>
      <description>What are Pictorials? Pictorials are papers in which the visual components (e.g. diagrams, sketches, illustrations, renderings, photographs, annotated photographs, collages) are the primary means of conveying information with at least, if not more, importance as the accompanying text.
Pictorials are not full papers. A good Pictorial requires precision and contextualization, but in terms of evidence and detail in argumentation, should aim at the level of a short paper rather than a full paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenters: How to Deliver an Inclusive Presentation</title>
      <link>/presenter-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/presenter-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>The DIS/C&amp;amp;C conferences are becoming increasingly diverse, with attendees from all over the world who represent varied gender, racial, ethnic, disability, and other identities. As a presenter, there are steps you can take to ensure that your message can be heard and understood by the widest possible audience. The following guidelines draw from and extend Kyle Rector’s Accessible Presentation Guide. Please refer there for more details.
When designing your slides, please:  use large font (size 30+) and high color contrast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provocations and Works-in-Progress</title>
      <link>/provocations_wips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/provocations_wips/</guid>
      <description>The DIS 2019 Provocations and Works-in-Progress (PWiP) track is a format that allows authors to propose novel, in-progress, and thought provoking research that may emphasize different values than what are usually promoted. The PWiP format is intended to facilitate discussion between authors and conference attendees. We welcome all submissions related to the design of interactive systems as well as the conference theme of Contesting Borders and Intersections.
We particularly welcome design research contributions that value:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session Chairs: How to Run an Inclusive Session</title>
      <link>/sc-guidelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sc-guidelines/</guid>
      <description>The DIS/C&amp;amp;C conferences are becoming increasingly diverse, with attendees from all over the world who represent varied gender, racial, ethnic, disability, and other identities. As a session chair, there are steps you can take to ensure that the session for which you are responsible is as inclusive as possible for attendees. The following guidelines complement Emory Berger’s Guide for Session Chairs towards promoting increased knowledge sharing and engagement of all our community members.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sponsorship</title>
      <link>/sponsor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sponsor/</guid>
      <description>In June 2019, the premier ACM conferences DIS and C&amp;amp;C will be joining forces in San Diego to bring together a diverse community of designers, scientists, artists, educators, and researchers.
Sponsoring this joint event is an ideal way to demonstrate your organization&amp;rsquo;s commitment to research on design and creativity, and to publicize this support to many leaders and students in the field. Sponsors play a vital role in sustaining the economic viability and proud tradition of strong participation for these conferences each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Volunteers</title>
      <link>/sv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/sv/</guid>
      <description>ACM DIS2019 Student Volunteers
Important dates:    Action Timeline     Student volunteer lottery registration system opens at chisv.org January 10th, 2019   Deadline to register for volunteer lottery March 25th, 2019   Applicants will be informed of their acceptance or waitlist status April 1st, 2019   T-shirt Design Contest Deadline April 26th, 2019    
T-Shirt Design Contest This year we call on students to design a cool t-shirt for both DIS and C&amp;amp;C SVs to wear while on duty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travel and Hotel Information</title>
      <link>/travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/travel/</guid>
      <description>ACM DIS 2019 will take place at:
Hyatt Regency Mission Bay  1441 Quivira Road  San Diego, California, USA, 92109 
The Hyatt Regency is located right on the waterfront in Mission Bay, a beautiful area with lots to do and explore. The hotel features views of the Pacific Ocean, Mission Beach, and the downtown San Diego skyline.
Attendees will be guaranteed a rate of $249/night + tax for standard run of house (click here to book with the conference rate).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshops</title>
      <link>/workshops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/workshops/</guid>
      <description>Please see the list of Accepted Workshops here.
We welcome proposals for hosting a workshop at DIS 2019 that align with the conference theme. Workshops offer unique opportunities for diverse groups of scholars, practitioners, and researchers to spend focused time on generative topics. A workshop format is ideal for working together on open, unresolved or controversial issues and developing a diverse range of outputs. Well designed and facilitated workshops attract broad interdisciplinary interest, inspire interaction between participants and foster community-building.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>